<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RuiyuRay&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RuiyuRay&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 22:57:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building System &amp; Environment Support for Tensorflow on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/post/build-tensorflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 22:57:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/build-tensorflow/</guid>
      <description>As promised, I will write about my experience with installation of tensorflow. The process looks daunting at first, but once you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the process, it&amp;rsquo;s nothing more than a couple lines of sudo commands.
Compatibility Before start, make sure to check compatibilities between the tools and packages that you&amp;rsquo;ll be building with. Take the following things into consideration:
- Ubuntu 16.04? 18.04? or others? Although NVIDIA explicitly specified different build packages for each version, sometimes you don&#39;t have to strictly follow them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Built of Multiple R Versions on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/post/mult-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:54:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mult-r/</guid>
      <description>Long time ago I built R-4.0.3 on Ubuntu system by following these guides: link1, link2. Briefly, I added GPG Key to APT (Advanced Package Tool) and added CRAN repository and directly retrieved R by apt.
$ sudo apt-key adv --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com --recv-keys E298A3A825C0D65DFD57CBB651716619E084DAB9 $ sudo add-apt-repository &#39;deb https://cloud.r-project.org/bin/linux/ubuntu bionic-cran40/&#39; $ sudo apt update $ sudo apt install r-base Recently, I ran into an issue with cellassign when analyzing single cell datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frquently Used Softwares</title>
      <link>/post/frq-used/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:41:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/frq-used/</guid>
      <description>Softwares used in works. Some require built from scratch.
Mac (iOS)  bash tools  brew tree   softwares  R    Ubuntu  Bioinformatics  samtools STAR umi_tools    Single cell biology  R  Seurat   python  geosketch    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you want to be a computational biologist?</title>
      <link>/post/on-comp-bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 16:49:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/on-comp-bio/</guid>
      <description>Recently I ran into this wonderful article published in Nature Biotechnology written by Nick Loman and Mick Watson, about how to become a computational biologist. The article is so brilliant and I thought I should dedicate my (actual) first post to write about it.
Understand your goals and choose appropriate methods  Key to good computational biology is the selection and use of appropriate software. Before you can usefully interpret the output of a piece of software, you must understand what the software is doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 19:59:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hosting my first Blog with Hugo on Github!
For a starter, I&amp;rsquo;ll document in this post how the blog is managed and used. I&amp;rsquo;ve setup the site by referring to here, here, and here.
The first link is particularly useful. I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted its file structure for setting up privately managed (/blog) and public sites (/public). Critically, the /public repo must be created with the following convention: https://github.com/RuiyuRayWang/ruiyuraywang.github.io Everytime contents in /blog is updated, run hugo -D to generate new site to /public and push /public to github accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
